字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
NORTHUMBRIA, NORTHERN ENGLAND VIKING SITE
（北英格兰 诺森比亚 维京人的地盘）
It was a Saturday.
那是一个星期六
Vikings bathe on Saturdays.
维京人星期六会洗澡
The English were aware of this custom.
英格兰人知道这个习俗
An enemy attack!
敌人来袭！
Burn it all! Spare no one, not even the women and children!
全部烧掉！ 一个不留 连女人和小孩也不要放过！
By the king's order, kill them all!
按照国王的命令 把他们都杀光！
Stand your ground! This is the turning point!
守住阵地！这就是转折点！
I killed Snorre!
我杀了斯诺雷！
Damn it.
该死
Spear group to the front!
好吧 长矛部队去前面！
Charge!
冲锋！
The battlefield went that way.
战场往那边去了
Why do I always get killed so soon?
为什么我总是马上被杀掉？
Corpses aren't supposed to talk, Thorfinn.
尸体不该说话的 托尔芬
You always just die, Faxi.
你总是直接死掉啊 法克西
Yeah.
是啊…
But after I die, I'll get to eat meat every day in Valhalla.
可是我死后 就可以每天 在瓦尔哈拉吃肉了
You can't go to Valhalla if you're not a strong warrior.
如果你不是强壮的战士 死后就不能进入瓦尔哈拉
I wonder if Mother and Ylva can go to Valhalla.
不知道母亲和攸尔法 能不能去瓦尔哈拉
Were you defeated, Thorfinn?
你被打败了吗 托尔芬？
You'll catch a cold dying in the snow.
你这么在雪地里装死会感冒的
You're leaving tomorrow?
你明天要走吗？
You're so lucky. Where are you going this time?
你真幸运 你这次要去哪里？
To Norway. I'm not going for fun.
去挪威 我不是去玩的
I'm going to trade.
我是去做生意的
I'll exchange woolen goods and furs for wine.
我要用羊毛制品和皮草去换酒
Then I'll come too!
那我也要去！
No.
不行
"Then I'll come too"? It's not for you to decide.
“那我也要去”？这可不是你说了算的
What an oaf.
真是个小气鬼
Don't blame me if you hit an ice floe.
撞到浮冰可别怪我
I want wine for the end of the year.
我需要年末用的酒
My father likes mead. Why don't you ask him to share with you?
我父亲喜欢蜂蜜酒 你为什么不让他跟你分享？
But there's a meaning to drinking wine.
可是喝酒有特殊的含义啊
I thought maybe this village would have wine.
我以为这个村子也许有酒
Thorfinn.
托尔芬
Run to your father and deliver a message.
跑去你父亲跟前 给他捎个信：
A battleship has arrived.
有一艘战舰驶过来了
What do you think of this, master?
你觉得这个怎么样 主人？
The hole should be sealed now.
这次 洞应该会被封起来了
Try filling it with water.
试着把里面注上水
This isn't easy to fix.
这个很难修
You hit it too hard, Thors.
你太用力了 托尔兹
Father!
父亲！
I'm here, Thorfinn.
我来了 托尔芬
Another battleship sailed in. A really big one!
又有一艘战舰开进来了 好大一艘！
They're asking for Thors the Troll and that's all.
他们要见托尔兹巨怪 仅此而已
By "Thors," do they mean that Thors?
他们说的“托尔兹” 一定是那个托尔兹 对吧？
The Troll?
巨怪？
These men seem highly trained.
那些人看起来训练有素
They look different from Halfdan's thugs.
他们看上去和哈夫丹的流氓可不一样
Oh, Thors!
哦 托尔兹！
Are they going to attack the village?
他们会攻击这个村子吗？
Jomsvikings! I have come.
约姆战士团！我来了
They're bowing to Thors.
他们在向托尔兹鞠躬呢…
I didn't think you would venture this far to find me,
我没想到你们会跑这么大老远来找我
Floki.
佛洛基
It's been a long time since the Norway campaign, Thors.
挪威战役已经是 很久以前的事了 托尔兹
I didn't think you'd be hiding at the end of the world.
我当然没有想到 你会躲在世界的最远端
State your purpose, Floki.
说明你们的来意吧 佛洛基
Then please grant us permission to land.
那么请先允许我们上岸
I wonder who exactly Thors is.
我想知道这个托尔兹到底是谁
I heard he fought in several wars in his youth.
我听说他年轻时参加过好几次战争
You're too loud, Ari.
你声音太大了 亚雷
He never speaks about himself.
他从来不谈及自己…
Hey, let me see too!
嘿 让我也看看！
He called them "Jomsvikings," didn't he?
他叫他们“约姆战士团” 对吧？
-Do you know who they are? -No idea.
你知道他们是谁吗？
Father seems a little angry.
父亲看起来有点生气…
They were ambushed while bathing.
他们在洗澡的时候遭到了伏击
Danes throughout the Danelaw were murdered by the English army.
丹麦区的丹麦人都被英军杀害了
And among them was Gunhilde,
其中包括
the younger sister of Sweyn, king of the Danes.
冈希尔德 丹麦国王斯韦恩的妹妹
Revenge for his sister.
为他妹妹报仇
King Sweyn now has an excellent reason.
斯韦恩国王有很好的借口
A great war will begin.
一场伟大的战争即将开始
As warriors, it is our time.
身为武士 我们的时刻到了
War?
战争？
The Jomsvikings will align with the Danish army.
约姆战士团将与丹麦军队结盟
We will launch an attack on England next spring.
我们明年春天要对英格兰发动攻击
Do as you wish.
随便你吧
This is a small village in the far north.
这是北边的一个小村庄
What other countries do beyond the North Sea does not involve us.
北海以外的国家做什么
That won't do.
那样不行
Our leader Sigvaldi's orders are to gather the whole Jomsviking armada.
我们的领袖西格瓦尔迪的命令 是召集整个约姆战士团舰队
There are no exceptions.
不能有例外
You understand, right?
你理解的 对吧？
That also includes deserters.
那其中也包括逃兵
Deserters?
逃兵？
Battalion commander of the Jomsvikings, Thors the Troll.
约姆战士团的营长 巨怪托尔兹
In this war, too…
这场战争…
you will take part.
你也要参加
Thors, think of it as a kindness from our leader.
托尔兹 你就把这当成是 我们领袖的好意吧
For 15 years, you've been missing, but you'll be welcomed back in battle.
你已经失踪十五年了
He is willing to overlook your past transgressions.
他愿意忽视你过去的过错
That is how much our leader values your ability.
我们的领袖就是这么重视你的能力
You came all this way in a warship to tell me that?
你乘战舰大老远跑来 就是为了告诉我这个？
You've agitated the villagers.
你们激怒了村民们
You've certainly changed, Thors.
你真的变了 托尔兹
Or perhaps this village changed you?
也许这个村子改变了你？
-Run! -Run away!
-快跑！ -跑啊！
That was a close one.
刚才真的好险
This is a good village.
这是个好村子
I can tell by the children.
看到孩子们 确实让我这么觉得
So far, the tribulations of war haven't touched their lives.
至今为止 他们的生活仍未 受到战争磨难的影响
Did you hear that? A war!
你听到了吗？ 战争！
-Wow! -My first one!
-哇！ -我的第一场战争！
They crossed the sea just to call on Thors to fight.
他们横渡大海 就是为了 号召托尔兹去跟他们作战
Your father's incredible.
你父亲太厉害了
But do you think he'll take us with him?
但你觉得他会带我们一起去吗？
Not you. You're too weak.
不会带你 你太弱了
What did you say?
你说什么？
You're no use if you're not strong.
如果你不强壮 那可没用
Well, on that front, I'll be fine.
在这一点上 我可没问题
None of you have killed a man. If you have that experience--
你们还没杀过人吧？
Sorry.
对不起
I, too,
我也不想
don't want to run a fool's errand.
浪费我的时间
If you tell me you won't fight in this war,
如果你告诉我你没有 参加这场战争的意愿
I'll fail to fulfill our leader's orders, and make him lose face.
我就会因为完不成领袖的命令 让他丢脸
I cannot leave empty-handed.
我不能空手而归
You understand, don't you?
你理解的 对吧？
The Jomsvikings.
约姆战士团
They're a battalion based in the port town of Jomsborg in Vendland.
他们是驻扎在温德兰港口城市 约姆斯堡的一个营
It's hard to believe that Thors was once a Jomsviking long ago.
很难相信托尔兹很久以前 也是一名约姆战士
Are they strong?
他们很强吗？
They are.
是的
They're so strong, the king of Vendland cannot make them pay taxes.
他们强到温德兰的国王 都没法让他们交税的程度
They are proud of being the strongest in the North Sea.
他们以自己是北海的最强者为傲
Withdraw! All units back to the ship!
撤退！ 所有小队都回到船上！
Withdraw!
撤退！
What was that? That guy gives me the creeps.
那是什么？他真让我毛骨悚然
You were spared, Ari.
他们放过你了 亚雷
Listen well, people of this village.
听好了 这个村里的人
I am the Jomsviking Floki.
我是约姆战士佛洛基
By my master's orders,
奉我主人的命令
Brave.
勇敢…
In response to our leader's request,
为了回应我们领袖的意愿
Thors has promised to deploy one warship.
托尔兹已经答应出动一艘战舰
Those of you who are confident, sail with Thors to Jomsborg!
你们当中有自信的人 跟着托尔兹一起去约姆斯堡吧！
Thors, I will meet you on the battlefield!
托尔兹 我会和你在战场上相见！
War!
战争！
Amazing!
太棒了！
How many years has it been?
我上次打仗是多少年前了？
We'll kill them all!
好 我们要杀了他们！
It's every man's dream to die on the battlefield!
死在战场上是每个男人的志向！
It's decided. Tomorrow, we ready the ship!
就这样决定了 明天我们开始准备战船！
Yeah!
好啊！
You couldn't refuse, could you, Thors?
你没法拒绝 是吧 托尔兹？
All the village has been dragged into it.
整个村子都被牵扯进去了
I was once very good at killing people.
之前 我杀别的人就算大功告成
But then one day…
可是后来有一天…
One day, I was suddenly sick of it.
有一天 我突然受够了
Kill… or be killed.
不是杀人…就是被杀…
That's why I fled
所以我才
from the battlefield.
逃离战场
I thought I had faked my death well enough.
我以为我装死装得够好了
Why not try it again?
那为什么不再试一次呢？
If I run away, they'll take revenge on this village in my place.
如果我逃跑 他们会用这村子 作为他们报仇的对象
The Jomsviking code does not forgive deserters.
约姆战士团的法典绝不原谅逃兵
The time has come for me to take responsibility for what I've done.
是时候让我为自己做过的事负责了
Get ready to pull!
好 准备拉！
Ready, set!
准备好…
Heave-ho!
嘿哟！
Heave-ho!
嘿哟！
Leif, I thought you were departing today.
嗯？雷夫 我以为你今天要出发
Thors asked me to wait.
托尔兹让我等等
I'll be sailing alongside that warship.
我会和那艘战舰一同出航
Is that so?
是吗？
That's certainly safer.
那样肯定更安全
If anything happens, we'll protect you!
如果出什么事 我们会保护你的！
I'll be counting on you.
我就指望你了
Pull!
拉！
They all seem real excited about the war.
他们似乎都对这场战争感到兴奋
That hurt!
好痛！
That damn Thorfinn!
那个该死的托尔芬！
Surround him!
把他包围起来！
Jerk!
混蛋！
We did it! We got Thorfinn!
我们成功了！ 我们抓到了托尔芬…
It hurts!
好痛！
What are you doing? Die,Thorfinn! You were just killed!
你在做什么？ 去死吧 托尔芬 你刚刚被杀死了！
Follow the rules.
遵守规则
-Yeah! -That's right!
-对！ -没错！
What's with him?
他怎么了？
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
Wait a minute, Thorfinn!
等一下 托尔芬！
All right. Raise it!
好吧 把它抬起来！
One, two, three!
一、二、三！
All right. Once more!
好 再来一次！
Thors!
托尔兹！
Could you look at something for me?
你能来帮我检查一下吗？
It's broken.
摔坏了
You played too roughly for children.
对小孩来说 你玩得太粗暴了
Keep this splint on for a month.
把这个夹板戴上一个月
Sorry, Thors.
对不起 托尔兹
Thorfinn did it!
是托尔芬干的！
He's been a pain lately.
他最近是个烦人精
He's out of control. We're not playing with him anymore!
他太过分了！ 我们不会再跟他玩了！
Really? My son?
真的吗？ 我儿子？
Yeah.
没错
I'm sorry about that.
我很抱歉
I'll have a word with him.
我来跟他谈谈
Don't worry about the kids.
别担心孩子们
He's only six but can hurt kids four or five years older.
但他只有六岁 对吧？
That's impressive.
挺让人佩服的嘛
He'll grow up to be an excellent warrior.
他会长成一名优秀的战士
He really is your son, Thors.
有其父必有其子啊 托尔兹
Wow!
哇！
You're giving me all of this, Father?
你把这些都给我了 父亲？
They're all from your grandfather's time.
这些是你祖父那时候的传家之宝
Fight to your heart's content!
尽情地去战斗吧1
Ari!
亚雷！
You look amazing, Ari!
你看起来好棒 亚雷！
Look what I got!
看看我这有什么！
This beauty can slice the head off a horse with one swing.
这宝贝能一下子就把马的头砍下来！
Wow, it's huge!
哇 好大！
-But my spear's a superior weapon. -Really? Wanna fight?
我的长矛才真是杀人机器呢！
Hey, wait a minute!
嘿 等一下！
Didn't I tell you to pick up your things? Are you listening?
我不是跟你说过 不要把东西到处乱丢吗？
Clean this up or I'll throw it out! Is that what you want?
收拾干净 不然我就把它丢出去！ 那是你想要的吗？
Fine. I don't want it.
没关系 我反正也不想要
What are you doing rummaging in the storage?
你在仓库乱翻做什么？
Where is my weapon?
我的武器呢？
What weapon?
什么？ 武器？
I need a weapon.
我需要一件武器
If I had one…
如果我有一件武器…
Do you think Father will take you on the ship if you have a weapon?
你觉得如果你有武器
I'll tell you now, you're wasting your time.
我现在就告诉你 你在浪费精力
You're just a puny child.
你还只是个小屁孩
Thorfinn?
托尔芬？
It's beautiful.
真美…
What's going on, Ylva?
怎么了 攸尔法？
Do you desire a sword, Thorfinn?
你想要一把剑吗 托尔芬？
Swords are tools for killing.
剑是杀人的工具
Who do you intend to kill with this?
你打算用这个杀谁？
The enemy.
杀…杀敌人
What enemies do you have?
你有什么敌人？
H…
哈…哈夫丹…
Listen to me, Thorfinn.
听我说 托尔芬
You do not have enemies.
你没有敌人
No one has enemies.
没有人有敌人
There are no people it is right to kill.
杀任何人都是不对的
Aren't you leaving for war tomorrow?
你明天就要去打仗了 对吧？
Will you not kill the enemy?
你要去杀敌人 不是吗？
I'm not a child.
我不是小孩子
You're lying to me.
你在骗我
I know you are!
我知道你在骗我！
Thorfinn!
托尔芬！
-Got you! -Watch it!
-打到你了！ -小心！
Helga.
赫尔加
Yes?
什么事？
Take care of him for me.
帮我照顾他
A west-northwest breeze and gentle waves.
西北风和缓 波浪温柔
Odin is in great spirits this morning.
奥丁今天早上心情很好
It's a good morning to depart.
今早适合出发
Yes.
好的
STREYMOY ISLAND, FAROE ISLANDS
（法罗群岛 斯特勒姆岛）
As I said, if I hit the mark with a left-handed throw
好 就像我说的那样
Oh, shut up.
哦 闭嘴吧
-Hit it and then talk. -Please.
-你先击中再说 -求…求你们…
Here I go, Christian monk.
我来了 基督徒和尚
Don't move, or I'll kill you.
别动 不然我会杀了你
You moved! You dodged it!
你动了！你刚躲开了！
-I'll kill you! -Move. It's my turn.
-我要杀了你！ -闪开 轮到我了
The priest.
牧师…
I told you not to move!
我告诉过你不要动！
You're terrible at this!
玩这个你太差劲了！
Hey, Jomsvikings.
嘿 你们这些约姆战士
Want a drink?
想喝一杯吗？
-They're serious, aren't they? -Let them be.
他们还真有礼貌 对吧？
They don't like cheap wine.
他们不喜欢便宜的酒
Your men are as reckless as ever, Askeladd.
你的人还是一如既往地粗鲁啊 阿谢拉特
They merely dislike Christians, Floki.
他们只是不喜欢基督徒 佛洛基大人
More importantly, tell me about this job you have.
更重要的是 赶紧说你的工作方案吧
My men and I have been bored waiting for you in this backcountry.
我和我的人在这个偏僻的地方 等你等得无聊死了
There are no major changes.
没有大的变化
Compensation is five pounds of gold.
赔偿金是五磅金子
You won't be paid until you produce the body.
尸体被确认前 你拿不到钱
You may do what you wish with his ships and cargo.
他的船和货物你可以随意处置
Kill Thors.
杀死托尔兹